{"data":[{"question":"Jane said, \" Excuse me.\" \n= Jane excused _________.","a":"her","b":"me","c":"myself","d":"herself","answer":"4","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n- Excuse oneself: to say politely that you need to leave a place","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"He never said, \" Help me.\"\n\n= He never cried ___ help.","a":"for","b":"over","c":"up","d":"against","answer":"1","explain":"\n\n- Cry for= ask for","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"She said, \"Good-bye, friends!\"\n\n= She ___ her friends good-bye.","a":"asked","b":"advised","c":"told","d":"bade","answer":"4","explain":"\n\n- Bid somebody good afternoon\/good morning","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The students said to me, \" How kind of you! \" \n= The students ___ me for my kindness.","a":"shouted","b":"exclaimed","c":"thanked","d":"asked","answer":"3","explain":"\n- \"How kind of you\" use when you want to express your thank to other people who help you","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"I said to her, \" What are you looking for?\" \n= I asked her what ___ looking for.","a":"she is","b":"she was","c":"is she","d":"was she","answer":"2","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"She said to me, \"What do you say to having a date with me tonight ? \" \n= She proposed that we ___ have a date that night.","a":"would","b":"should","c":"might","d":"could","answer":"2","explain":"\n-\" What do you say to having a date with me tonight?\": imply suggest\/offer that somebody should do something= should is correct","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"\" Hurrah! I've passed the exam!\" he said. \n= He exclaimed ___ that he had passed the exam.","a":"in delight","b":"in joy","c":"with joy","d":"for delight","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Hurrah- happy, pleasant= joy \n- Exclaim with","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" Hello! Where are you going?\"\n\n= He ___ me and asked where I was going.","a":"told","b":"shouted","c":"asked","d":"greeted","answer":"4","explain":"\n\n- Hello: used to great someone","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The priest said, \" God save my country ! \" \n= The priest ___ that God might save his country.","a":"prayed","b":"hoped","c":"worshipped","d":"shouted","answer":"1","explain":"\n- \"Pray\" often used with god","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The man said to her, \" Do you know where the post office is ?\" \n= The man asked her ___ where the post office was.","a":"that she knows","b":"that she knew","c":"if she knows","d":"if she knew","answer":"4","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"}]}